Guide to the Anson Phelps Stokes Autograph Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Anson Phelps Stokes Autograph Collection
1713-1958
MS 402
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(10 boxes)
A collection of autograph letters and manuscripts gathered by Anson Phelps Stokes and designed to document the history of Yale University.
Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Anson Phelps Stokes in 1929.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Stokes Autograph Collection was formed by the Reverend Anson Phelps Stokes (1875-1958) mainly during the 22 years he served as Secretary of the University from 1899 to 1921. From 1924 to 1939 he served as Canon of the Protestant Episcopal Cathedral in Washington, D.C. The collection was made "for the purpose of creating a deeper and more intelligent interest in Yale history and biography." Letters of the most important alumni, accompanied by engravings and printed sketches taken from Appleton's CYCLOPOEDIA OF AMERICAN BIOGRAPHY (1887) were exhibited for a number of years in Woolsey Hall. The Reverend Stokes commemorated 158 of the Yale men represented in the collection in his MEMORIALS OF EMINENT YALE MEN (Yale University Press, 1914), and twenty letters from the collection are printed in the two-volume work. The forward quoted below describes the purpose of the collection.
After his death in 1958, President A. Whitney Griswold eulogized the Reverend Stokes in the following words: "Anson Phelps Stokes was one of the great men in Yale's history. Yale owes much of its present strength to his devotion to the university ideal and his farsighted and forceful pursuit of that ideal during his career as Secretary. Thereafter, as a leader in both religion and learning, his services to church and civil state fulfilled abundantly the terms of Yale's charter. All Yale men are grateful to him and will honor his memory."
Arrangement
The correspondence is arranged alphabetically.
Autographs; Yale University -- Biography; Yale University -- History
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1713-1958; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series, which is alphabetically arranged, contains letters, documents, and notes of 655 Yale graduates, including some who received recognition for their achievements in business, politics, the ministry, and academic life. In addition to manuscript material, biographical information and quite frequently a portrait, are also available for a majority of the graduates; this is especially useful for less famous graduates. Most of the documents date from the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries, although some are from the twentieth century, and one, a photostat copy of the title page of a book by John Davenport, is dated 1663.
  - Abbot, Henry Larcom (1831-1927), 1911 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    TLS to (Anson P. Stokes)
  - Adams, Andrew (1736-1797), 1792 February 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Summons to appear in court, to Benjamin Farnum
  - Adams, John (1772-1863), 1829 August 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Certificate that Sereno T. Abbot graduated from Andover
  - Adams, William (1807-1880), 1874 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    ALS to "Author of the Three Gardens"; also portrait and biographical notes
  - Addington, Isaac (1645-1715), 1696 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Memorandum (Bono) for Robert Saunders
  - Alden, Rober (1754-1836), 1779 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    ALS to Col. A. Burr
    [Transferred to Burr Family Collection]
  - Allen, Diarca Howe (1808-1870), 1842 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    ALS to William W. Nevin
  - Allen, Timothy (1715-1806), 1745 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    ALS to Eleazar Wheelock
  - Andrews, Ethan Allen (1787-1858), 1851 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    ALS to Messrs. Harper and Bros.
  - Ashley, Jonathan (1712-1780), 1767 June 4 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    ALS to "Dear Sister" (Mrs. Elizabeth (Scott) Williams Smith)
  - Ashmun, George (1804-1870), Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    ALS to unknown
  - Atwater, Rev. Jeremiah (1773-1858), 1802 August 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    ALS to Messrs. Thomas and Thomas
  - Atwater, Noah (1752-1802) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Ms. Sermon nos. 1773 and 1774
  - Austin, Rev. Samuel (1760-1830), 1910 December 20 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Ms. Sermons on Matthew 22:21
    also TLS A. P. Stokes to Professor George Perkins re Samuel Austin
  - Avery, Rev. David (1746-1818), 1770 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Backus, Rev. John Chester (1810-1884), 1861 July 15, 1911 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    ALS to L. C. Bayles, also biographical sketch re J. C. Backus
    ALS from B. Steiner to A. P. Stokes
  - Bacon, Rev. Leonard (1802-1881), 1877 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    ALS to Dr. Josiah Gilbert Holland
    also biographical note and portrait
  - Bacon, Rev. Leonard Woolsey (1830-1907), Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Ms. drawing: His own epitaph from class autograph book
  - Badger, George Edmund (1795-1866), 1851 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    ALS to R. P. Anderson
  - Badger, Rev. Joseph (1757-1846), 1813 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Subsistence account from Oct 1-Dec 31, 1812, paid
  - Bailey, Ebenezer (1795-1839), 1826 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    ALS to Benjamin Poore
  - Baker, Osmyn (1800-1875), 1823 April 9 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    ALS to unidentified correspondent
  - Baldwin, Abraham (1754-1807), 1788 June 5 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    ALS to Seaborn Jones; also biographical note
  - Baldwin, Henry (1780-1844), 1813 June (Box 1, Folder 24)
    ALS to Samuel Huntington; also biographical note
  - Baldwin, Roger Sherman (1793-1863), 1834 May 29, 1853 June 17 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    ALS to Nathan Smith
    ALS to Messrs. Michael Nourse & Co.
  - Baldwin, Simeon (1761-1851), 1802 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Certificate of deposit in the Connecticut District Court of oath subscribed by Christopher Leffingwell and Jabez Perkins on Benjamin Ames
  - Baldwin, Hon. Simeon Eben (1840-1927), 1904 February (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Autograph acceptance of invitation
  - Baldwin, Theron (1801-1870), 1835 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    ALS to Rev. Julian M. Sturtevant
    also 1 ALS and 3 TLS re the T. Baldwin ALS and portrait
  - Bannard, Otto Tremont (1854-1929), 1909 October 26,1909 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    TLS to A. P. Stokes; also election announcement
  - Bardeen, Charles William (1847-1924), 1866 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Printed permission to C. W. Bardeen to attend church
    service outside the college
  - Barker, George Frederic (1835-1910), Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Biographical information only
  - Barlow, Joel (1754-1812), 1774 March 21,n.d (Box 1, Folder 32)
    ALS to Gen. Nathanael Greene
    photostat ALS to William Whann
    also portrait and biographical notes
  - Barnard, Rev. Frederick Augustus Porter (1809-1889), 1872 August 9 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    ALS to Samuel B. Ruggles; also portrait and biographical information
  - Barnard, Henry (1811-1900), 1868 May 30, 1863 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Address to Congress (and copy in Stokes Hand)
    ALS to unidentified; also portrait and biographical notes
  - Bacon, Ezekiel (1776-1870), 1814 June 21, 1911 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    ALS to Jedidiah Huntington
    TLS to Stokes re E. Bacon
  - Barstow, Rev. Zedekiah Smith (1790-1873), 1843 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    ALS to Cyrus S. Richards
  - Bartlett, Truman Howe (1835-1922), (1866) August 17 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    ALS to E. E. Salisbury
    [Transferred to Salisbury Family Papers]
  - Bates, Isaac Chapman (1780-1845), 1841 December 28 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    ALS to Thomas Aspinvale
  - Battell, Robbins (1819-1895), 1871 July 13 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    ALS to William Cothren
  - Beach, Rev. Abraham (1740-1828), 1800 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Ms. Sermon
  - Beecher, Edward (1803-1895), 1855 August 7 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    ALS to "Dear Sir"
    [Transferred to Beecher Family Papers]
  - Beecher, Lyman (1775-1863), 1827 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Biographical note and portrait
    [All items transferred to Beecher Family Papers]
  - Beers, Clifford Whittingham (1876- ), 1907 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    ALS to A. P. Stokes
    [Transferred to Clifford Whittingham Beers Papers]
  - Beers, Henry Augustin (1847-1926), 1913 November 27 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Bellamy, Joseph (1719-1790), 1763 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    ALS to Rev. Samuel Hopkins
    Biographical note
    [All items transferred to Joseph Bellamy Papers]
  - Bement, Edward (1848-1931), 1867 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Certificate showing his presence at divine worship outside the college
  - Benham, Henry Washington (1813-1884), 1854 February 7 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    ALS to "My dear Harry"
  - Benjamin, Judah Philip (1811-1883), 1853 April 17, 1861 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    ALS to Asbury Dickens
    ALS to Governor John Letcher; portrait and biography
  - Bidwell, Walter Hilliard (1798-1881), 1866 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    ALS to accompany autograph picture (now in photo file)
  - Bingham, Hiram (1831-1908), 1905 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    ALS to James M. Whiton; biographical notes, and portrait
  - Bishop, Abraham (1762-1844), 1813 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    ALS to James H McCulloch
  - Bishop, William Henry (1847-1928), 1912 October 26 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Bissel Clark (1782-1857), Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Autograph as Governor of Connecticut
  - Bissell, Wilson Shannon (1847-1903), 1911 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Autograph with TLS to A. P. Stokes from Philemon
    F. Sturges re signature and portrait
  - Blake, Eli Whitney (1795-1886), 1868 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Copy of ALS to A. Webster; biographical notes and portrait
  - Blake, William Phipps (1826-1910), 1882 December 21 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    ALS to L.E. Jones; also biographical notes
  - Bliss, George (1793-1873), 1837 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    ALS to Wm. Dwight
  - Blodget, Henry (1825-1903), Undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Biographical notes only
  - Booth, Rev. Chauncey (1783-1851), 1819 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    ANS attesting the profession of faith of Maj. Elias Buell and wife Sarah
  - Boudinot, Elias (1740-1821), 1818 December 14 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    ALS to Elihu Chauncey
  - Bourne, Edward Gaylord (1860-1908), 1901 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    ALS to Rev. A.P. Stokes; also biographical notes and portrait
  - Bowen, Jabez (1739-1815), 1771 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    ADS being a true copy of the warrant for the removal from Providence R.I. to Boston Mass. of Sarah Magee
  - Boyd, John (1799-1881), 1861 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    Printed form notifying John H. Simmons of his election to Conn. State Senate
  - Brace, Charles Loring (1826-1890), (1854) August 22 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    ALS to Miss Lynch autograph; also portrait
  - Bradley, Stephen Row (1754-1830), 1806 October 7 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    ALS to Stephen Jacobs Esq.; also biographical notes and picture
  - Brainerd, David (1718-1747), 1743 May 21, 1747 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Facsimile from his diary; also biographical notes
  - Brainard, John Gardiner Calkins (1796-1828), 1913 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    ALS to A.P. Stokes from Ira H. Brainard
    re: J.G.C. Brainard; also biographical notes
  - Brainard, John (1720-1781), 1765 September 26 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Autographed receipt
  - Brewer, Chauncey (1743-1830), 1787 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Brewer, David Josiah (1837-1910), 1901 July 3 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    ALS to A.P. Stokes; also biographical notes and portrait
  - Brewer, William Henry (1828-1910), 1884 January 19, 1864 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    ALS to Chester Alan Arthur [Transferred to William Henry Brewer Papers]
    ALS to Geo. J. Brush [Transferred to Brush Family Papers]
    Biographical notes and portrait
  - Brewster, Chauncey Bunce (1848-1941), 1909 April 13 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    TLS to A.P. Stokes
  - Brinton, Daniel Garrison (1837-1899), 1885 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    ALS to Miss Alger; also biographical notes and portrait
  - Bristed, Charles Astor (1820-1874), n.y. March 19 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    ALS to Egbert L.Viele; also biographical notes and portrait
  - Bromley, Isaac Hill (1833-1898), Undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
    Biography notes only
  - Brown, Benjamin Gratz (1826-1825), 1846 February 24 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    ALS to Holly Brand; also biographical notes and portrait
  - Brown, Ernest William (1866-1938), 1908 February 8 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    ALS to A.P, Stokes
  - Brown, Henry Billings (1836-1913), 1910 May 20 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    ALS to A.P. Stokes
  - Brown, Joseph Emerson (1821-1894), 1869 August (Box 2, Folder 79)
    ALS to unidentified correspondent; also biographical notes and portrait
  - Brown, Samuel Robbins (1810-1880), 1880 March 10 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    ALS to Dr. Syle; also biographical notes and portrait
  - Brown, Solyman (1790-1872), 1871 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    Autographed Sermon; also biographical notes
  - Brownson, Nathan (1742-1796), 1781 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    ALS to Skey Eustace
  - Brush, George Jarvis (1831-1912), 1909 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    ANS to A.P. Stokes; also biographical notes and portrait
  - Brush, William (1827-1895), Undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
    ANS to "Friend Adams"
  - Buckingham, Samuel Giles (1812-1898), 1844 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    ALS to Prof. E. E. Salisbury
  - Buckingham, William Alfred (1804-1875), 1862 July 28 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    ALS to Pres. Woolsey
  - Buell, Samuel (1716-1798), 1793 June 9 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    ALS to Dr. Williams
  - Bull, Nehemiah (1701-1740), 1734 November 8 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    ALS to Stephen Williams
  - Bumstead, Horace (1841-1919), Undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Burr, Rev. Aaron (1716-1757), 1757 August 27 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    Order on Mary Alexander to pay Peter V.B. Livingston
    also biographical notes and portrait
    [All items transferred to Burr Family Collection]
  - Burr, David (1757-1825), 1797 April 3 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    Judgment against Mary Silliman before court
  - Burr, Rev. Enoch Fitch (1818-1907), 1878 April 13 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    [Transferred to Salibury Family Papers]
  - Bushnell, David (1742-1824), 1787 December 14, 1783 July 11 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    ALS to Capt. Thomas Machin
    Facsimile of signed provision return
  - Bushnell, Rev. Horace (1802-1876), 1864 December (Box 2, Folder 94)
    2 pages of Sermon on Oratory and Preaching
  - Calhoun, John Caldwell (1782-1850), 1834 May 27 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    ALS to John S.Wellford; also biographical notes portrait
  - Calhoun, William Barron (1795-1865), 1837 February 15 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    ALS to Mr. Dickerson, Secretary of Navy
  - Camp, Henry Ward (1839-1864), 1864 April 10 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    ALS to Henry B. Camp; also biographical notes
  - Clay, Cassius Marcellus (1810-1903), 1857 January 14, 1880 January 5 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    Autographed sentiment signed
    ALS to B. Perry; biographical notes; portrait
  - Clayton, John Middleton (1796-1856), 1850 July 17 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    ALS to diplomatic and consular agents of the U.S.
    biographical notes and portrait
  - Cleaveland, Rev. John (1722-1799), 1783 April 28 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    ALS to Rev. Joseph Dana
  - Cleaveland, Moses (1754-1806), 1796 March 7 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    ALS to Maj. John McCallan
  - Codman, John (1782-1847), 1846 October 6 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    ALS to Edward E. Salisbury
  - Cogswell, Dr. Mason Fitch (1761-1830), 1796 January 11 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    ALS to Col. Samuel Huntington
  - Coit, Rev. Thomas Winthrop (1803-1885), 1838 June 22 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    ALS to S. G. Drake
  - Coleman, Lyman (1796-1882), 1855 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    ALS to Mr. Gayley
  - Colt, LeBaron Bradford (1846-1924), 1867 February 26 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    Permission to L. B. Colt to attend church service outside the college
  - Colton, Walter (1797-1851), Undated (Box 2, Folder 107)
    ALS to Capt. Patridge; biographical notes
  - Conant, Shubael (1711-1775), 1755 December 23 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    Autographed Military Certificate
  - Cooke, Joseph Platt (1729-1816), 1785 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    Summons to the Sheriff of the county of Litchfield for Josiah Starr and Joseph Mygatt
  - Cooke, Samuel (1711-1788), 1760 March 29 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    Deed of land conveyed by John Turner to Nathan Bears
  - Carter, Franklin (1837-1919), (19-) October 17 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Catlin, Jacob (1758-1826), 1796 April 27 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    Autographed sermon; also biographical notes
  - Chandler, Thomas Bradbury (1726-1796), Undated (Box 2, Folder 113)
    Autographed sermon fragment signed in another hand
  - Chapin, Augustus Lyman (1795-1878), 1874 July 13, 1869 February 10 (?) (Box 2, Folder 114)
    Honorable dismissal to E.H. Lewis from
    Beloit College
    ALS to "Dear Br. Alexander"
  - Chauvenet, William (1820-1870), 1843 November 7, 1912 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    ALS to Dr. Samuel Jones
    TLS from his son Wm. Chauvenet to A.P. Stokes re: his father Wm. Chauvenet
  - Chenevard, John. (1733-1805), 1787 September 7 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    ALS to "Dearly Beloved" John Woodworth
  - Cheney, Ward (1875-1900), 1898 July 27 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Chester, John (1749-1809), 1794 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    Quit-Claim to rights of land in Susquehanna Purchase
  - Chipman, Nathaniel (1752-1843), 1818 September (Box 2, Folder 119)
    ALS to Charles H. Williams; also biographical notes
  - Chittenden, Russell Henry (1856-1943), 1909 June 6 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Clark, Josiah (1814-1878), 1870 July 15 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    ALS to Prof. Packard
  - Clark, Thomas March (1812-1903), 1861 September 23 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    ALS to Messrs. M.M. Bragg, D.F. Heffner and Thomas Foster
  - Clarke, Rev. Richard (1738-1824), 1784 December 25 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    ANS to Col. Clapman; also epitaph from Newspaper of R. Clarke
  - Cooper, James Fenimore (1789-1851), 1827 May 12, 1834 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 124)
    ALS to Professor Benjamin Silliman [Transferred to Silliman Family Papers]
    ALS to Daniel Desmond Esq.; biog notes, portrait
  - Cornelius, Rev. Elias (1794-1832), 1830 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 125)
    Printed form filled in giving names of Amherst students given aid by American Educational Society
  - Couch, Jesup Nash (1778-1821), 1814 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 126)
    ALS to Calvin Pease
  - Cowles, Rev. Henry (1803-1881), 1868 March 21 (Box 2, Folder 127)
    ANS to James Kilbourn
  - Crapo, William Wallace (1830-1926), 1878 June 28 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    ALS to Hon. Charles Devens
  - Cutler, Manasseh (1742-1823), 1783 May 23 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    ALS to Benjamin Lincoln; biographical notes, portrait
  - Cross, Wilbur Lucius (1862-1948), 1911 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Cutler, Rev. Timothy (1683-1765), Undated (Box 2, Folder 131)
    Autographed list of marriages performed in 1746 and 1747 by Timothy Cutler
  - Daggett, David (1764-1851), 1827 March 30, 1805 June 4 (Box 2, Folder 132)
    ALS to (Stephen Titus) Hosmer [Transferred to David Daggett Papers]
    ALS to "Dear Sir" (mutilated with photostat copy) [Lost]
  - Daggett, Naphtali (1727-1780), 1758 January 7, 1779 February 28 (Box 2, Folder 133)
    2 autographed sermons
  - Dana, Edmund Lovell (1817-1889), 1869 AUG 21 (Box 2, Folder 134)
    ALS to Dr. Stoner
  - Dana, Edward (1849-1935), 1911 November 3 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Dana, James Dwight (1813-1895), 1874 May 30 (Box 2, Folder 136)
    ALS to Prof. Ogden Rood; also biographical notes and portrait
  - Dana, Samuel Whittlesey (1760-1830), 1789 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 137)
    ALS to His Excellency John Hancock
  - Darling, Thomas (1720-1789), 1785 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 138)
    Autographed warrant for the whipping of Thomas Murphy
  - Davenport, John (1597-1670), MDCLXIII (Box 2, Folder 139)
    Photostat of title page of "A Discourse about Civil Government in a New Plantation"
  - Davies, Thomas Frederick (1831-1905), 1878 June 11, 1911 May 19 (Box 2, Folder 140)
    ALS to Henry Babcock
    ANS to A.P. Stokes
  - Davis, Rev. Henry (1771-1852), 1837 November 19 (Box 2, Folder 141)
    ALS to Thomas F. Davies
    also article re: Hamilton College of which Davis was president
  - Davis, John (1787-1854), 1838 July, 1839 December 2 (Box 2, Folder 142)
    ALS to "Sir" (Mr. Keen?)
    ALS to unidentified correspondent; also biographical note and portrait
  - Dawes, Henry Laurens (1816-1903), 1868 February 24 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    ALS to ____ Briggs; also biographical notes and portrait
  - Day, Aaron (1715-1778), 1761 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    Autographed deed conveying a piece of land in New Haven to Nathan Beers
  - Day, Clarence (1874-1935), 1908 February 4 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    AN to A.P. Stokes with cartoon of himself in bed
  - Day, Clive (1871-1951), 1907 December 25 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Day, Jeremiah (1773-1867), 1803 December 3, 17, 1804 March 3, 12, 1806 January 15, February 22, 1802 July 5 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    6 ALS to Benj. Silliman [Transferred to Silliman Family Papers]
    Photostat ALS to Benj. Silliman [Transferred to Silliman Family Papers]
  - Day, Thomas (1777-1855), 1816 June 3 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    ALS to Elisha Gleason
  - Dean, Gilbert (1819-1870), 1858 July 8 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    ALS to Isaac Toucey
  - Deane, Silas (1737-1789), 1766 Dec 17 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    ALS to Thomas Mumford; biographical notes; portrait
  - DeForest, David Curtis (1774-1825), 1821 September 11 (Box 3, Folder 151)
    Formal note of regrets to Jeremiah Day and the Corp.
  - DeForest, Heman Packard (1839-1914), 1865 September 14 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    ALS to T. D. Woolsey
  - DeForest, John Hyde (1844-1911), n.y. June 17, 1903 May 23, 1909 May 17 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    ALS to "Dear Dunning"
    ALS to "Dear Old Fellow"
    ALS to "Dear Folks"; biographical notes; portrait.
  - DeForest, Robert Weeks (1848-1931), 1909 December 24 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    ALS to Edward S. Dana
  - deKay, Charles Augustus (1848-1935), 1867 April 8 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    Certificate of church attendance
  - Delafield, Edward (1794-1875), 1837 April 17 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    ALS to Luther Bradish Esq.
  - DeLancey, William Heathcote (1797-1865), 1852 June 17, 1864 July 25 (Box 3, Folder 157)
    Autographed statement to Rt. Rev. Dr. Green
    ALS to T. D. Woolsey; biographical notes; portrait
  - Dexter, Franklin B. (1842-1920), 1897 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    ALS to A. P. Stokes; biographical notes; portraits
  - Dexter, Henry Martyn (1821-1890), 1882 May 19 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    ALS to Professor Thompson
    Autographed copy of the oldest Christian hymn
  - Dickinson, John Dean (1767-1841), 1804 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 160)
    ALS to Martin P. Vosburgh
  - Dickinson, Jonathan (1688-1747), 1733 June 9 (Box 3, Folder 161)
    Bill of sale of Negro girl by Richard Scudder of Dickinson
  - [not assigned] (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - Douglas, David Bates (1790-1849), 1825 February 25 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    ALS to Gen. Hez. Howe
  - Duffield, Samuel Willoughby (1843-1887), Undated (Box 3, Folder 164)
    Les Neiges D'Antan" (Ms. poem)
  - Dummer, Jeremiah (1680?-1729), 1706 (Box 3, Folder 165)
    Legal document signed
  - Duncan, Carnett (1800-1875), 1848 December 6 (Box 3, Folder 166)
    ALS to C. S. Todd
  - Durant, Henry (1802-1875), 1872 November 12 (Box 3, Folder 167)
    ALS to President Gilman [Transferred to Daniel Coit Gilman Papers]
    Biographical notes; portrait
  - Dutton, Henry (1796-1869), 1837 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 168)
    ALS to Hezekiah Howe
  - Dwight, Benjamin Woolsey (1780-1850), 1820 August 24 (Box 3, Folder 169)
    ALS to Lemuel Punderson
  - Dwight Theodore (1796-1866), Undated (Box 3, Folder 170)